http://www.hawkins.biz/privacy-notice

Privacy Notice
The Hawkins Group is formed of Hawkins & Associates Limited, Hawkins & Associates (Trustees) Limited, Hawkins (International) Limited, Gardiner Fire Investigation Limited, Hawkins & Associates (Singapore) PTE Limited, Hawkins & Associates (Hong Kong) Limited. This Privacy Notice explains how we collect data from you and how the data is used.What information do we collect about you? Marketing dataOperational data (assignments we are appointed on by our clients)Human Resources dataShareholder dataCategories of Personal Data heldThe following is a list of the types of personal information held by the Hawkins Group, we will not hold all types of information on each individual.Clients (Marketing and Operational) NameJob TitleAddressEmail addressTelephone numberCCTV footage if visiting one of the Hawkins Group premisesInsured, Insured’s employees, other claim related third parties, members of the public (Operational) NameAddressEmail addressTelephone numberDate of birthInsurance policy numberClaim reference numberMedical recordsCriminal record dataDetails of the claimCCTV footage if visiting one of the Hawkins Group premisesHuman Resources NameAddressEmail addressTelephone numberDate of birthGenderEmergency contact detailsFinancial, payroll and tax informationEmployment contract recordsAbsence records (including health records)Performance recordsRecruitment recordsTermination of employment recordsDue diligence recordsCCTV footage at the Hawkins Group premisesShareholders NameAddressEmail addressTelephone numberShareholding recordsBank account detailsHow do we collect data about you?Clients (Marketing and Operational) Directly
from you when you register for marketing purposes Submission
of Contact Us and/or training forms on
website Directly
from you when you place an assignment with usInsured, Insured’s employees, other claim related third parties, Members of the public (Operational) Supplied to us by our clientSupplied to us by another third party related to the assignment we are appointed onDirectly from youSocial media platformsWhere the personal data is provided by our client this will typically be subject to the terms and conditions of your insurance policy, failure to allow us to process the data may lead to you being in breach of the terms and conditions of your insurance policyHuman Resources Directly from youSupplied to us by a recruitment agencyAgencies carrying out due diligencePrevious employer for reference purposesMedical practitionerSocial media platformsShareholders Directly from youBy a privileged relationLawful basis for collecting information about youAll personal data collected by the Hawkins Group is collected in the legitimate interests of the Group in order to carry out its activities.
There may be additional lawful basis as detailed below.Clients (Marketing and Operational) Legitimate interests of the Group in order to carry out its activitiesInsured, Insured’s employees, other claim related third parties, Members of the public (Operational) Legitimate interests of the Group in order to carry out its activitiesProcessing is necessary for the performance of a contract (insurance contract)Processing is necessary for an insurance purposeProcessing is necessary for the purpose of legal proceedingsProcessing is necessary for the reasons of public interest in the area of public healthHuman Resources Legitimate interests of the Group in order to carry out its activitiesProcessing is necessary for the performance of a contractProcessing is necessary for compliance with a legal obligationProcessing is necessary for the reasons of public interest in the area of public healthProcessing is necessary for compliance with employment lawShareholders Legitimate interests of the Group in order to carry out its activitiesProcessing is necessary for compliance with a legal obligationPurpose for processing the information and how will we use that information?Clients (Marketing and Operational)Data held for marketing purposes is used to make contact with those who may be interested in our services and if you have previously appointed us, to make you aware of other services that we provide.Client data held for operational purposes is used as part of an assignment we are appointed on.Insured, Insured’s employees, other claim related third parties, Members of the public (Operational)Operational data is held to analyse as part of an assignment we are appointed on by a client.Human ResourcesData held by our Human Resources team is used to facilitate our recruitment process and to manage the day to day operations of our business.ShareholdersShareholder data is held to manage individual shareholdings.CCTV Footage from Hawkins Group premisesCCTV data is held for security purposes only.Automated Decision Making or ProfilingThe Hawkins Group does not use any form of automated decision making or profiling for any purposes.MarketingIf we hold your data for marketing purposes you have the right at any time to stop us from contacting you for marketing purposes or giving your information to other members of the Hawkins Group. If you no longer wish to be contacted for marketing purposes please email dataprotection@hawkins.biz. Sharing your Personal DataPersonal Data may be shared with the clients and suppliers of The Hawkins Group and other assignment related third parties.Personal Data held by the Group may be transferred to: Other members of the Hawkins GroupClientsOther assignment related third partiesThird party service providers to provide and support our Information Technology servicesAuditors and professional advisorsLaw enforcement or other government and regulatory agenciesTransfer of data outside of the United KingdomWhen data is processed within the Hawkins Group some of this data may be processed outside of the United Kingdom and the European Economic Area (EEA). Where data processing does occur outside of the United Kingdom and the EEA the same technical and organisational controls are implemented. The Hawkins Group has adopted the European Union Standard Contractual Clauses for the transfer of Personal Data.Where the Hawkins Group’s sub-processors process data outside of the United Kingdom and the EEA those sub-processors have the appropriate safeguards and/or contractual obligations in place to ensure the safety and confidentiality of Personal Data.Access to your information and correctionYou have the right to request a copy of the information that we hold about you. If you would like a copy of some or all of the personal information that we hold about you please either email us at dataprotection@hawkins.biz or write to us at:Data Protection Officer 120 Cambridge Science Park Milton Road Cambridge CB4 0FZWe want to ensure that your information is accurate and up to date, you may ask us to make corrections to your data.Right to erasureYou have the right under Article 17 of the General Data Protection Regulations to request us to erase your personal data. If you would like some or all of your personal data erased from our system please either email us at dataprotection@hawkins.biz or write to us at:Data Protection Officer 120 Cambridge Science Park Milton Road Cambridge CB4 0FZRetention periodThe retention period for personal data will be assessed depending on the nature of the information held. The retention policy will vary depending on whether data has been collected for Marketing, Human Resources, Operational, Shareholding or Security purposes. The retention policies are regularly reviewed and personal data is not held for longer than is necessary.Lodge a complaint with the supervisory authorityYou have the right to lodge a complaint with the supervisory authority if you are not satisfied by the way in which we store and process your personal information. In the UK the supervisory authority is the Information Commissioner’s Office (ICO). The contact details for the ICO are:Website: www.ico.org.ukTelephone: 0303 123 1113 Address: Information Commissioners Office Wycliffe House Water Lane Wilmslow SK9 5AFThis privacy notice was updated on 6 May 2020.
Contact Us
Enquiry type
Generic
New Instruction
Feedback
Submit
Submitting this contact form will enter your details into our contacts database and we will reply to
your request as soon as possible. We will also retain your details so we may contact you from time
to time. You can ask us to remove your details at any time. For details, see our Privacy Notice.
